[Music]
so
do
hello everyone and welcome to a cold
rainy day in the cascade mountains
i had a very well-loved book of folk
tales when i was a child and one of my
favorite stories was about a very wise
and old tree man who lived at the top of
a hill and could accurately predict the
weather just by sniffing the air
i always thought it was a funny idea and
yet now that i've been here for over two
years i can say that i understand
there's a very definite shift in the
scent of this environment when the
seasons change when the air isn't mixed
in with the smell of petrol and crowded
places you discover it carries with it a
thousand aromatic notes of the earth
right now i can smell sage and cedar as
well as the minty by defrost
the autumn gnomes are no doubt
collecting the very last of the apples
and the squirrels are topping their
stores
[Music]
in last week's video some expressed to
me that they're hoping to move and start
a new life soon and are in a time of
transition
also a few said that they believed i was
living off-grid and very isolated from
people dozens if not hundreds of miles
away from civilization
i wanted to clear this up in regards to
my location not to discourage your
lifestyle preference only to explain my
own
i also felt that perhaps it could be
helpful to share some less desirable
things i face while living in a rural
area
knowing that nowhere is perfect and each
place has challenges depending on who
you are
[Music]
so
due to respecting the privacy of my
neighbors i do not show their homes but
i can assure you they are there i'm
neither off-grid nor am i isolated and i
enjoy about a 15-minute drive from town
hundreds of people live similarly in
this area i prefer things that way and i
will explain why
in relation one of the biggest
challenges i face living here is social
connection
when i lived in the city it was easier
for me to meet people within my age
group and that share my interests
this isn't always as facilitated in the
countryside for the simple fact that
there simply are less people
for example in the city i loved spending
time with my peers who spoke spanish had
lived in the caribbean or had also grown
up in a military family i automatically
felt like i had so much in common with
them while there are young people with
similar backgrounds here it isn't as
likely and so i rely a little more on
communicating with others by email and
social media
now this isn't to say you cannot connect
with an incredible community wherever
you are but for me it took a little more
work and creativity to do that out here
and i think your own personality and
social needs should be considered when
making a move to a rural area because
despite my introversion this has been
tricky for me
[Music]
that is one of the reasons i enjoy
living close to town i admire people who
are in very isolated and off-grid
locations they are impressive and must
have a lot of mental strength because i
am not like that
i find that loneliness is a very real
thing that can creep up on me if i'm too
far removed from other people
it isn't easy to live like that if
anything being isolated and alone could
be very hard to deal with if you are
like me and that's something i know
because i live sonia town and i even
struggled with feeling disconnected from
others when i first moved here
thankfully through working as a teacher
and getting involved that has changed
over time
in addition i also feel much safer being
near people it's unrealistic for me to
live isolated as i have a job that
requires me to work in town and i cannot
work remotely i don't have a lot of free
time nor the knowledge or ability to
invest the cost and energy needed in a
homestead to keep it functional
another big reason i live near town is
that i can easily get help if i need it
for emergencies and otherwise
if you saw my last video you know that
i've experienced medical scares in my
family before
my father had a heart attack over a year
ago and he's still a very healthy and
fit and young person in my opinion so
examples like that make me want to
always be within a short drive to the
hospital
that's not always possible if you're
very isolated and i think that's
something everyone should take into
consideration especially if you have a
handicap medical issues pets children or
like me need peace of mind
that is one of the main reasons i live
like i do i just thought it was
important to explain how because i
wouldn't want anyone to get a different
impression and i also believe we can
live in alignment with the earth and
take the planet into consideration no
matter how or where we live in the city
or otherwise
we can just take simple steps to learn
about our environment and support
organizations who want to make lasting
change
[Music]
i've always thought a great thing to do
when considering a move is if feasible
to find a small rental in your location
of interest do seasonal work and
experience what it's like to live there
throughout the year before committing to
a completely new environment
i know of several people who bought
houses in the summer here only to
realize they hate the gruelling winters
and sadly there are many homes that are
left empty the majority of the year
making it hard for people working in
town to find a place to live
that isn't a problem all small towns
face but it is a challenge to be aware
of
in short i encourage anyone to follow
their heart and where and how they want
to live
but there is rarely a need to rush into
things i planned my move for a long time
before i actually left the city and i
think i could have planned some more
it was well worth it to skip the stress
of not being prepared
i think that no matter how beautiful the
location or the home getting into a
situation that is stressful or
financially unstable will ruin the
experience
and while i'm here talking about more
challenging aspects of rural life i hope
that my channel is a testament of the
reasons i do love to live here and
wouldn't want to be anywhere else
[Music]
anyway i hope this video gave you some
things to consider if you've ever
thought about living rural this is only
speaking from my limited perspective
i think there are pros and cons to
wherever and however you live and it's
important to recognize every side of it
and choose to love the life you have
anyway
i have chosen to love mine and i wish
you the very best on your journey this
year
take care and i will see you next week
in regards to the things that i
mentioned that i've been
struggling with at times in regards to
living here
i decided to
let this era of working more from home
and from an office come to an end
because i would really like to
start working in town again even though
i haven't quite decided what type of
part-time job i will do long-term i
decided to help out my local bookstore
in the next couple months because they
will be having more business due to the
holidays and they really needed an extra
person that already had experience being
a bookseller and with the system and
could talk about books in an appropriate
amount of time which i can do that is
the plan i will be working there for a
while and then go from there and see
where the journey takes me i really
enjoyed working from home i know a lot
of people have been working from home
for the first time in their lives
since the world changed
and
i
think there are many positives to it
that i really enjoy and that's why i
want to still keep
working from home at least a little bit
but i do miss people and connecting with
new people
and seeing my friends more often and
it just seemed like the right course of
action to take
it has been a wonderful and fruitful
journey of learning a lot about myself
and finding creative ways to
resolve things that i miss about the
city and it's been wonderful and i've
met so many incredible people and i hope
to meet many more anyway i wish you all
well i will keep you in the know of what
i'm up to i have some very exciting
exciting possibilities on the horizon
and
i am very excited to share with you but
until things are set in stone i don't
feel like i can
so
i'm very excited for the future because
i will be taking some part-time work i
decided to close down my etsy shop at
the end of november because i wasn't
sure i'd be able to keep up with it in
december while working and
doing everything else so
it felt right to
pull back a little bit and be able to
keep making videos of course but
ease the workload a little bit which has
grown a lot this year and it has been
too much at times to be honest i'm
looking forward to being a bookseller
for a while and seeing where that takes
me and revisiting that job because that
is something i really love to do when i
got out of university i hope you all
have a wonderful day and i will see you
next week